Hamilton Ude Ikedi

I am an enthusiastic learner, a detail oriented innovator and emerging leader. My experience majors in NodeJS and JavaScript and as a Full Stack Software Engineer, I have created and participated in transformative software solutions, orchestrating every facet from planning and design to deployment. I have great affinity towards user-friendly web applications, trends and best practices as seen in my projects.

EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Lagos — Software Engineer

APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

- Collaborated closely with 20 product owners, partners and stakeholders to discern client requirements and deliver with an average customer satisfaction rate of 80%.
- Developed 4 secure, test-driven applications, adhering to best practices for project completion.
- Engineered robust backend servers and APIs, employing NodeJS, Express and GraphQL.
- Proficiently managed diverse database management systems: SQL(MySQL, Postgres) and NoSQL(MongoDB).
- Streamlined app deployment and teamwork via Docker containerization.
- Managed seamless collaboration among teams using Git and GitHub in over 10 mini projects and advanced web applications.
- Championed CI/CD implementation across various project repositories.

Reboth Finance, Cross River — Social Media/ Digital Services Administrator

AUGUST 2022 - MARCH 2023

- Engaged in collaborative team efforts with a group of 3 tech experts to design, develop and render digital services to over 200 clients.
- Orchestrated 20% average monthly lead generation via targeted emails and feedback channels.
- Amplified audience reach through strategic signup forms and landing pages, accelerating email expansion.
- Leveraged ConvertKit for streamlined workflow automation, subscriber management and engagement tracking.

Orchid Road, Lekki Peninsula II, 106104, Lagos State.

+2347036954656

Email:

<u>dehamiltonglobal@gmail.co</u> <u>m</u>

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamilton-ude-ikedi-07744a16a/

Github:

https://github.com/UIHamilton995

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- Node.js
- Express
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- GraphQL
- ApolloServer
- Html5
- Css
- React.js
- Tailwind.css
- Bootstrap
- Docker
- Firebase
- Digital Ocean
- CI/CD
- Unit & Integration testing(TDD)
- Agile Leadership & Methodologies
- Jira

PROJECTS

PLUTUS — Financial Investment app

- A meeting point for investment companies to meet willing investors.
- Users can transfer and receive funds from other users.
- **Technologies:** Node.js, Typescript, Express, Postgres, React, Redux Toolkit, Tailwind.
- Link: https://github.com/UIHamilton995/plutus-financial-app

DECAHEALTH — Hospital Management App

- Store and manage comprehensive patient records digitally.
- Allow patients to book appointments online, reducing waiting times..
- Digitize and centralize patient health records for easy access and sharing.
- Link: https://github.com/UIHamilton995/DecaHealth-Hospital-App

SCIENTIFIC CALCULATOR

- A mathematical calculator that performs from simple to complex arithmetic calculations.
- Technologies: Vanilla JavaScript, Html5, Css.
- Link: https://github.com/UIHamilton995/scientific-calculator

EDUCATION

Enugu State University of Science & Tech, Enugu — BSc

Applied Biochemistry – Second Class Lower SEPTEMBER 2012 - AUGUST 2016

CERTIFICATIONS

- SCRUM Fundamentals Certified (SFC) MARCH 2023 Credential ID 974913
- AgileSCRUMstudy Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile Issued Mar 2023 · No Expiration Date

SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Emotional Intelligence
- Communication
- Problem solving
- Adaptability
- Time management
- Leadership